Dhaval Tejlavwala

Parramatta, NSW, 2150 | Mobile: 0414136120 | Email: tejlavwaladhaval@gmail.com

Website: www.dhavaltejlavwala.com

CARRIER OBJECTIVES

Solutions-driven and highly energetic programmer with three years record of commended performance in modular and object-oriented programming. Also well-versed in all phases of the software and website development lifecycle, with a strong working knowledge of salesforce technologies, machine learning techniques, data analysis. The completion of my master's degree in ICT from WSU with a specialisation in web and mobile computing and my passion for software development make me an ideal candidate for this position.

CAPABILITIES FRAMEWORK

- Proficient in frontend development using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap.
- Experienced in backend development using Java, C#, VB.Net, MVC 5, VB, OOP, NodeJS, Entity Framework.
- Specialised with working on Azure platform, SQL server 2012, stored procedure, functions and view to manage the database.
- Skilled in setting up dev-ops process using Azure dev-ops, Git source control, and maintain multiple system environments
- A better understanding of Salesforce administration work as well as customisation using Apex code
- Significantly able to manage multiple small-scale projects and successfully deliver it with the best quality, to budget and on time as project manager and known for working with internal and external stakeholders, also, directly deal with clients.
- Skilled in machine learning and data analysis applications using Scikit-learn, NLTK, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, and Plotly. Also familiar with R programming in data science
- Proven writing and communication skills with strong analytical and problem-solving capabilities.
- Adaptive person, hard worker, friendly, team player and with a positive attitude to solve any problem

SKILLS

- Software Application Development
- Coding and Scripting
- GUI Design
- Debugging and Troubleshooting
- User Training and Support
- Testing and Documentation

- Data Analysis
- Google analytics
- Predictive Model Designing
- Salesforce Administration and Development
- System integration

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Programming: ASP.Net, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C, PHP, Python, Swift 3

Frameworks: MVC 5, Bootstrap, jQuery, AngularJS, Silverstripe, MongoDb, Scikit learn, Pandas, Django, Umbraco, Azure Cloud Technologies

Software: Visual Studio 2019, Visual Studio Code, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, JustInMind,

Jupyter, Android Studio, MS Office Suite (Access, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Project)

Systems: Windows, Macintosh OS X, Linux Ubuntu

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Application Developer

Centrepoint Alliance – Sydney

June 2018 - Present

Maintaining high-scaled Salesforce CRM, developed multiple private and public websites, and provide full technical support to internal and external users.

- Reports to Head of Technology Delivery and Architecture
- Liaising business verticals (sales and marketing) to understand the business problems and recommend solutions
- Design and develop user interfaces to Internet/intranet applications by setting expectations and features priorities throughout the development cycle
- Completes applications development by coordinating requirements, schedules, and activities; contributing to team meetings; troubleshooting development and production problems across multiple environments and operating platforms.
- Assist and educate business users/consultants with modern technologies/products that are rolled out in the organisation
- Responsible for the management, supervision, and administration of the corporate Salesforce application portfolio
- Take complete ownership of projects and lead the projects right from the requirements phase to release phase
- Decommission legacy applications by refactoring them with the latest cutting-edge Microsoft technologies and migrate them to Azure platform.
- Keep me up to date by researching new internet/intranet technologies and software products; participating in educational opportunities

Test Analyst (Intern)

Jul 2017 – Sep 2017

Western Sydney University – Sydney

Worked as a test analyst following the commended performance in program atlas.

- Wrote meaningful test cases/platforms/procedures in Quality Centre and log defects from testing into service now dataset
- Prepared quality data for test execution, environment plans and testing schedule
- Learnt and use ITIL processes to create project knowledge articles in ITIL tool (ServiceNow)
- Tested and documented integration end-to-end scenarios between ServiceNow and HP Service Manager and increased efficiency by 27%
- Recommended to expand technology from HP cloud services to Microsoft Azure

Android Developer

Jul 2015 – Dec 2015

Accrete Infotech – Surat, IND

- Developed optimised project concepts and maintained optimal workflow
- Communicated with customers and developers to understand existing problems and analyse optimal solution
- Wrote clean, clear, efficient, well-tested, and maintainable code
- Worked with the UI team to design the appropriate icons and displays for the various mobile screens
- Conduct high-quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability
- Contributed to the maintenance of the existing apps with fixing issues, adding automated tests, improving performance, architecture, design and code quality

Infinity Technology – Surat, IND

Built and customized web applications and tools using advanced development and coding techniques. Manage all phases of application design -- from coding and prototyping through system testing, integration and deployment.

- Worked as a full-stack developer in the team of four on ask4ticket.com (online movie booking system) and built various web modules using asp.net MVC framework, objectoriented programming and VB.net
- Responsible to manage all movie theatre API's works efficiently, real-time, and without interruption in payment gateway
- Developed number of interactive modules for data analysis using jQuery grid, charts.js and jqplot.js libraries
- Designed and developed a single-page website irechargeapp.com for an ERP on mobile device - smartphone-based business management solution for telecom supply chain using bootstrap
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front-end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code
- Involved in managing and designing high scale database, stored procedures, views and function using MS SQL Server Management Studio R2/2012

Junior Developer (Intern)

Jul 2013 - Jun 2014

Eastern Techno Solution – Surat, IND

Joined an internship program for a great career with some hands-on experience in technology and opportunity to work on the live projects or to insinuate my own ideas

- Managed database and web site programming tasks (primarily using Java, HTML and bootstrap), working an average of 20 hours per week
- Redesigned Internet and intranet pages. Used SEO best practices to optimize the website for search engine rankings and improved functionality of company database
- Worked on different live android projects and uploaded more than twenty applications on google play store

Web Developer (Intern)

Jun 2013 – Jul 2013

Dakshin Gujarat Vij Company Ltd. – Surat, IND

Worked as a web developer to convert the DOS-based AT&C Loss project to the web-based system.

- Designed and developed interactive web pages to manipulate AT&C Loss data
- Documented integration scenarios between the DOS-based system to web-based

EDUCATION

Professional Year Program for ICT

Feb 2018 - Nov 2018

Performance Education, Sydney

Master's in information and Communication Technology

Feb 2016 - Dec 2017

Western Sydney University, Sydney

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Jun 2010 - June 2014

Gujarat Technological University, Surat, IND

PUBLICATIONS

An assessment into the characteristics of award-winning papers at CHI

May - 2018

Scientometrics – Springer International Publishing

- Performed textual analysis on academic papers of CHI's conference and figured out the characteristics of award-winning papers with four other researchers from Western Sydney University
- Built an optimised predictive model using machine learning and data analysis techniques in Python

PROJECTS

Sentimental analysis on IMDB movie reviews

Feb 2017 – May 2017

Western Sydney University – Sydney

- Performed sentiment classification on IMDB movie reviews' dataset containing a set of 25,000 movie reviews for training, and 25,000 for testing
- Implemented three classification models Logistic Regression, Linear SVM with and without Parameter Selection and Random Forest. Also, the program shows accuracy and time for each classification model

Dietitian Application

Feb 2016 - May 2016

Western Sydney University – Sydney

- A Web application focusses on dietitians' perspectives who searches a meal or food for their clients and set a diet plan for them. The app shows the nutrition facts about food and meal
- An application developed in HTML, JavaScript and Bootstrap framework for frontend and backend managed with PHP. Also, all nutrition facts come through API integration (nutritionix.com)

Traffic Analysis Using Image Processing

Jun 2013 – May 2014

Sarvajanik College of Engineering and Technology – Surat, IND

- Windows-based application for monitoring and analysis of road traffic using image processing and pattern recognition libraries (Aforge and EmguCV) in C# language
- Used CCTV footage of different areas in the Surat city and measure traffic density in different time
- Analysed collected data on the bases of the time duration of the day using MS Excel